Steven Grootaert

an architect and now a programmer *

I've been an architect since I was a kid - officially I became licensed in 2020. It's been an incredible journey. Along the way I've been told I'd make an excellent programmer. When I began writing code I found it engaging. The two share much in common; we navigate abstract concepts and create unique solutions to ill defined problems. As an architect I think through many possible outcomes evaluating every constraint or opportunity from initial concept to final construction. Coordinating the efforts of multiple disciplines and prioritizing the needs of the client while simultaneously keeping the big picture in view and managing details comes with the territory of practicing architecture. I am fastidious by nature and leverage my architectural experience in everything I do.

* I am currently enrolled in the Back-End Engineer career path at Codecademy to further develop my skill set as a programmer.

FUNCTIONAL SKILLS:

Agile methodology, problem solving, troubleshooting, divergent creativity, visual communication, critical observation and systems thinking, organization, portfolio development, customer service, addressing and resolving business challenges.

EDUCATION:



Codecademy: Pro Career Path and Skills Development

- Jul 2021 - current_www.codecademy.com
Continued professional development focusing on back-end engineering.
Completed certificates in C#, CSS/HTML, and Git/Github.



Eleven Fifty Academy: Software Development Immersive Learning Program

- Aug 2020 - Feb 2021 _ Indianapolis, IN

12-week immersive learning program for Software Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+hours of logged coding time and training.



Master of Architecture + Master of Science Sustainable Design

2009 - 2012 _ University of Minnesota _ Minneapolis, MN
Concurrent with my M.Arch I also took coursework to obtain an M.S. in
Sustainable Design. I gave a TEDxUMN talk about my M.Arch and M.S. thesis
work after being nominated by the Dean of the College of Design.

\sim

steven.grootaert@gmail.com



github.com/StevenGrootaert



linkedin.com/in/steven-grootaert



dev.grootaert.com



Indianapolis, IN



917.744.1676

LANGUAGES

C# / ASP.NET Framework - HTML / CSS object oriented programming

SKILLS / TECHNOLOGIES

Pair Programming - Agile Methodolgies Relational Databases - N-tier - MVC Razor - Bootstrap - Github / Git Responsive Webdesign - SQL Server REST API Development - Postman

SELECT PROJECTS:

DoWhat – ASP.NET MVC Web Application

Overcome decision fatigue by deciding what needs to be done with the time you have.

By creating lists of 'to-do' items and then linking them to categories and expected duration to complete, tasks can be assigned to the user based on those constraints. As a final project for the course many of the components for this project came together through self guided research and experimentation. This web application was designed using N-Tier architecture and deployed on Azure.

Slot Me – .NET API Web Application

Connecting artists with free time to clients who want to book gigs.

In a small group we learned to collaborate on different parts of the app independently via Github and verified our endpoints with Postman. After extensive outlining of our data structure with foreign keys, models and services, I managed the repository and made pull requests for merging our code into a finalized project.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Ball State University

Adjunct Instructor of Architecture, Aug 2020 - current (Indianapolis, IN)

I've been teaching as a part-time adjunct instructor in the Architecture Department at the Indianapolis Campus for Ball State University for several years. Using my professional experience as an architect, I teach students the process of architectural documentation, how to present to community stakeholders and guide their design endeavors.

Kinlin Rutherfurd Architects

Intermediate Architect, Apr 2019 - Oct 2020 (New York, NY)

Working on various high-end residential projects in NYC and the Hamptons. I managed drawing sets used for regulatory approval and construction documentation. I met with clients and contractors to ensure the best possible design build experience for all parties involved.

